# **Alexander Melocco**

#### aleximelocco@gmail.com • 0414 109 645

Projects Portfolio/GitHub link: <a href="https://alexmelocco.github.io/alexmelocco/">https://alexmelocco.github.io/alexmelocco/</a>

#### **Profile**

Motivated and dedicated university student with a passion for personal growth and a proven history of dedication to all facets of work. Pursuing a Bachelor of Software Engineering (Honors) and Law at UNSW, I possess a diverse background in co-curricular and academic endeavors, including being honored with the Premier's Award for all around excellence in 2022. I am currently employed at Talent 100 as a mentor, where I have gained valuable experience in fostering collaborative relationships and maintaining a strong work ethic. I also dedicate my time to social impact within the community with involvements in volunteering and Enactus seeing me explore social impact opportunities nationally. I am excited to hopefully both challenge and apply my skills and knowledge within all my future commitments.

# Technical Skills

- Python
- Java
- C++/C#/C
- JavaScript

- CSS/HTML
- Socket Programming Web Development.
- Machine learning
- Collaborative work experience (Gitlab, GitHub) MS applications

# **Education & Qualifications**

- UNSW (2022-current)
- Bachelor of Engineering (Honors)/Law
- 2023 Enactus National Social Impact Competition finalist
  - Knox Grammar School (2012-2021)
- 99.30 ATAR
- 2021 Silver Academic Award Knox
- 2021 Prefect Leader
- 2019 FED Debating Cup winner
- 2019 Kokoda Trail Participant
  - RSA/RCG Licensed

- Premier's award for all around excellence (2022)
- 2021 Silver Co-curricular Award Knox
- 2018 International Da Vinci Decathlon winner
- Bronze Duke of Edinburgh award
- Company Medic for Knox Cadet Unit

# Professional Experience

• **Talent 100** May 2022 – Current

Academic tutor and mentor for Talent 100

• Enactus UNSW Jan 2023 – Current

Events director for management, synthesis and hosting events for UNSW Enactus which is a society with a primary focus on entrepreneurial social impact and making positive worldwide change through real projects.

#### • Knox Grammar School Academic Prefect Leader 2020 – 2021

Responsible for interactive app development to allow cohort online coordination, and resource gatherer. Worked in the advertisement, marketing and event planning for student led operations.

• UNSW Microfinance Consulting Group January 2022 – December 2022

Responsible for event's planning, synthesis, and execution with the goal of helping other students enter the realm of consulting.

• Lime Seven January 2022 – April 2022

Sales consultant at Lime Seven which is a marketing and sales company.

Australian Venue Co / Bungalow 8 April 2022 – November 2022

Bartender and beverage attendant

• Art of Smart Education May 2022 – December 2022

Academic tutor for Art of Smart

#### References

• Jennifer Kim – Head of Academic at Talent 100

j.kim@talent-100.com.au

0432 608 855

• David Nguyen – Student Services Manager at Talent 100

d.nguyen@talent-100.com.au

0423 065 405

### Additional Information

- Cultural Experience: Travel often, and challenge myself in various physical disciplines, including embarking on Kokoda Trail in Papua New Guinea, and touring Europe for a Da Vinci Decathlon Competition
- Social impact and volunteering: Proud advocate for volunteering and championing projects that directly affect social progression. National Enactus Social Impact competition saw me go to Melbourne to compete is presenting the most socially transformative plans. Actively volunteer within my community and work within non-profit teams that work to develop biodegradable prosthetics (Enactus Prockets). Also involved in Tech4Impact which is a collaboration with the African STEM Education Initiative that focuses on lack of Stem education in Uganda.
- **Software Projects**: Strong passion for projects. My current double major with law and software engineering comes from a genuine passion towards possible contribution to the modernization of law. Also passionate in self-development with projects such as Flower iris recognition.
- Personal interest: Avidly enjoy physical sports such as boxing and powerlifting. Also love reading.